{
    "questions": [
        {
            "options": [
              "A. Manasa",
              "B. Kali",
              "C. Durga",
              "D. Parvati"
            ],
            "question": "The Deodhani dance is associated with the worship of which goddess",
            "answer": "A. Manasa"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Jorhat",
              "B. Barpeta",
              "C. Nagaon",
              "D. Kamrup"
            ],
            "question": "In which district, the Bhortal Nritya dance was developed",
            "answer": "B. Barpeta"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Supimphaa",
              "B. Suklamphaa",
              "C. Suhungmung",
              "D. Suramphaa"
            ],
            "question": "Which Ahom King is also known as the Dihingia Raja",
            "answer": "C. Suhungmung"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Suklenmung",
              "B. Supatphaa",
              "C. Suhungmung",
              "D. Suramphaa"
            ],
            "question": "Who moved the Ahom capital to Garhgaon from Bakata",
            "answer": "A. Suklenmung"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Swarnagiri",
              "B. Ratnapur",
              "C. Sadiya",
              "D. Dimapur"
            ],
            "question": "Which one was not a capital city of Chutiya Kingdom",
            "answer": "D. Dimapur"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Sankhadhwajpal",
              "B. Durlabhanarayan",
              "C. Dharmadhwajpal",
              "D. Nityapal"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the last ruler of Chutiya Kingdom",
            "answer": "D. Nityapal"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Nara Narayan",
              "B. Biswa Singha",
              "C. Lakshminarayan",
              "D. Bali Narayan"
            ],
            "question": "Who established the Koch Dynasty",
            "answer": "B. Biswa Singha"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Gopinath Bordoloi",
              "B. Bishnuram Medhi",
              "C. Bimala Prasad Chaliha",
              "D. Golap Borbora"
            ],
            "question": "During which Chief Minister's tenure, the Assam Official Language Act was enacted, which made Assamese languagethe sole official language of the state",
            "answer": "C. Bimala Prasad Chaliha"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 6",
              "B. 7",
              "C. 8",
              "D. 9"
            ],
            "question": "Till 2020, how many person from Assam received the Padma Bhushan Award",
            "answer": "D. 9"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Nirmal Prabha Bordoloi",
              "B. Nalini Bala Devi",
              "C. Pushpalata Das",
              "D. Chandraprabha Saikiani"
            ],
            "question": "Who was elected as the first Women President of Assam Sahitya Sabha",
            "answer": "B. Nalini Bala Devi"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Omeo Kumar Das",
              "B. Bishnu Prasad Rabha",
              "C. Hemchandra Barua",
              "D. Phani Sarma"
            ],
            "question": "Who is also known as Lok Nayak in Assam",
            "answer": "A. Omeo Kumar Das"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1974",
              "B. 1977",
              "C. 1981",
              "D. 1984"
            ],
            "question": "Bhupen Hazarika won his first Padma award (Padma Shri) in the year",
            "answer": "B. 1977"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Hem Barua",
              "B. Hema Bharali",
              "C. Mukul Chandra Goswami",
              "D. Amalprava Das"
            ],
            "question": "Which Assamese social worker has been awarded with Jamnalal Bajaj Award in the year 1981",
            "answer": "D. Amalprava Das"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Lakshminath Bezbaroa",
              "B. Gopinath Bordoloi",
              "C. Omeo Kumar Das",
              "D. Bishnuram Medhi"
            ],
            "question": "Who had translated The Story of My Experiments with Truth, the autobiography of Mahatma Gandhi, into Assameselanguage \"Mor Satya Aneshwanar Kahini\"",
            "answer": "C. Omeo Kumar Das"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Hem Barua",
              "B. Kuladhar Chaliha",
              "C. Kushal Konwar",
              "D. Nabin Chandra Bardoloi"
            ],
            "question": "Which independent activist is also known as \"Tyagbir\"",
            "answer": "A. Hem Barua"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 15th",
              "B. 17th",
              "C. 20th",
              "D. 22nd"
            ],
            "question": "What is the rank of Assam in the Ease of Doing Business released by the Union Finance Minister",
            "answer": "C. 20th"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 83.4%",
              "B. 85.9%",
              "C. 87.3%",
              "D. 89.2%"
            ],
            "question": "As per the data released by National Statistical Office, what is the literacy percentage of Assam",
            "answer": "B. 85.9%"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 4th",
              "B. 5th",
              "C. 6th",
              "D. 7th"
            ],
            "question": "What is the rank of Assam in India in literacy as per National Statistical Office report released in 2020",
            "answer": "B. 5th"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Bhogeswari Phukanani",
              "B. Kanaklata Barua",
              "C. Dipali Barthakur",
              "D. Pratima Barua Pandey"
            ],
            "question": "The film \"Hastir Kanya\" was made on the life and works of",
            "answer": "D. Pratima Barua Pandey"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Kaziranga National Park",
              "B. Manas National Park",
              "C. Nameri National Park",
              "D. Assam State Zoo cum Botanical Garden"
            ],
            "question": "The Assam Forest Museum is located in",
            "answer": "D. Assam State Zoo cum Botanical Garden"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1869",
              "B. 1872",
              "C. 1874",
              "D. 1875"
            ],
            "question": "The Northbrook Gate, which was constructed to welcome British viceroy Lord Northbrook was built in the year",
            "answer": "C. 1874"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Urpad Bil",
              "B. Dipor Bil",
              "C. Son Beel",
              "D. Chandubi Lake"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the 2nd largest wetland in Asia and Largest wetland in India as well as in North East",
            "answer": "C. Son Beel"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Suklenmung",
              "B. Sutingphaa",
              "C. Suremphaa",
              "D. Sudangphaa"
            ],
            "question": "Which Ahom king ordered the execution of Hari Bhuyan, son-in law of Sankardeva",
            "answer": "A. Suklenmung"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Treaty of Guwahati",
              "B. Treaty of Kamatapur",
              "C. Treaty of Majuli",
              "D. Treaty of Charaideo"
            ],
            "question": "Under which treaty of 1563, Ahom kingdom accept the Koch overlordship",
            "answer": "C. Treaty of Majuli"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Sukaphaa",
              "B. Sudangphaa",
              "C. Susenphaa",
              "D. Sujinphaa"
            ],
            "question": "Who ruled for the longest period of 49 years as Ahom King",
            "answer": "C. Susenphaa"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Kolong Express",
              "B. Dhing Express",
              "C. Nagaon Express",
              "D. Kamakhya Express"
            ],
            "question": "Hima Das is also known by the nickname",
            "answer": "B. Dhing Express"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 3",
              "B. 4",
              "C. 5",
              "D. 6"
            ],
            "question": "Total number of oil refineries in Assam is",
            "answer": "B. 4"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Guwahati",
              "B. Tezpur",
              "C. Jorhat",
              "D. Dhubri"
            ],
            "question": "Which city of Assam was also known as \"Haruppeswara\" in ancient times",
            "answer": "B. Tezpur"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Guwahati",
              "B. Kolkata",
              "C. Silchar",
              "D. Shillong"
            ],
            "question": "Which one city was elected as capital of Assam Province in British India, created in 1912",
            "answer": "D. Shillong"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 18",
              "B. 21",
              "C. 25",
              "D. 32"
            ],
            "question": "Total number of district courts in Assam is",
            "answer": "B. 21"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 37",
              "B. 48",
              "C. 56",
              "D. 67"
            ],
            "question": "As per the 2019 edition of Ethnologue, published by SIL International, USA - Assamese is the ____ th most speakinglanguage in the World",
            "answer": "D. 67"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Chakrashila Wildlife Sanctuary",
              "B. Garampani Wildlife Sanctuary",
              "C. Pani Dihing Wildlife Sanctuary",
              "D. Dehing Patkai Wildlife Sanctuary"
            ],
            "question": "Which wildlife sanctuary is decided to upgrade to national park by the Assam government in the month of July, 2020",
            "answer": "D. Dehing Patkai Wildlife Sanctuary"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Pani Dihing Wildlife Sanctuary",
              "B. Garampani Wildlife Sanctuary",
              "C. Amchang Wildlife Sanctuary",
              "D. Dehing Patkai Wildlife Sanctuary"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is a Govt recognised Bird Sanctuary in Assam",
            "answer": "A. Pani Dihing Wildlife Sanctuary"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Bohag",
              "B. Jeth",
              "C. Aahar",
              "D. Kati"
            ],
            "question": "In Assamese calender, which month have 32 days",
            "answer": "C. Aahar"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Tezpur",
              "B. Jamugurihat",
              "C. Jakhalabandha",
              "D. Dhing"
            ],
            "question": "The \"Bare Sohoriya Bhaona\" is held in which city of Assam",
            "answer": "B. Jamugurihat"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Nalbari",
              "B. Jorhat",
              "C. Barpeta",
              "D. Nagaon"
            ],
            "question": "The \"Kumar Bhaskar Varma Sanskrit and Ancient Studies University\" is located in which district",
            "answer": "A. Nalbari"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1838",
              "B. 1842",
              "C. 1846",
              "D. 1852"
            ],
            "question": "The last Ahom king Purandar Singha was died in the year",
            "answer": "C. 1846"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Dhubri",
              "B. Goalpara",
              "C. Cachar",
              "D. Karimganj"
            ],
            "question": "The wetland \"Son beel\" is located in which district",
            "answer": "D. Karimganj"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Maniram Dewan",
              "B. Kanaklata Barua",
              "C. Kushal Konwar",
              "D. Lachit Borphukan"
            ],
            "question": "On 1st October 2020, Indian Coast Guard (ICG) commissioned a fast patrol vessel (FPV) in Kolkata after the name of",
            "answer": "B. Kanaklata Barua"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. KR Choudhary",
              "B. B. M. Rajkhowa",
              "C. Raj Mohan Ray",
              "D. Subashini Sankaran"
            ],
            "question": "Who was appointed as the first Assam Police Chief on October 1 in 1951",
            "answer": "A. KR Choudhary"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1968",
              "B. 1971",
              "C. 1974",
              "D. 1977"
            ],
            "question": "In which year, High Court of Assam and Nagaland, was renamed as Gauhati High Court",
            "answer": "B. 1971"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1921",
              "B. 1924",
              "C. 1926",
              "D. 1929"
            ],
            "question": "When the All India Congress Committee session was hosted in Guwahati",
            "answer": "C. 1926"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Jorhat",
              "B. Guwahati",
              "C. Sivsagar",
              "D. Nagaon"
            ],
            "question": "Which city is also known as \"The Cultural Capital of Assam\"",
            "answer": "A. Jorhat"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Biswanath College of Agriculture, Biswanath Chariali",
              "B. Bholanath College, Dhubri",
              "C. Bajali College, Barpeta",
              "D. J.B. College, Jorhat"
            ],
            "question": "The first non-government college of Assam is",
            "answer": "D. J.B. College, Jorhat"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. September, 2016",
              "B. Novemebr, 2016",
              "C. January, 2017",
              "D. March, 2017"
            ],
            "question": "When Majuli is formally declared as a district in Assam",
            "answer": "A. September, 2016"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Barnadi forest",
              "B. Molai forest",
              "C. Barail forest",
              "D. Dihing forest"
            ],
            "question": "Which forest is single-handedly planted by Jadav Payeng",
            "answer": "B. Molai forest"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1902",
              "B. 1906",
              "C. 1908",
              "D. 1912"
            ],
            "question": "In which year, Kaziranga was designated a \"Reserve Forest\" for the first time",
            "answer": "C. 1908"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Dhemaji",
              "B. Majuli",
              "C. NC Hills",
              "D. Karbi Anglong"
            ],
            "question": "Which one district is declared as the first carbon free district in Assam (also in India)",
            "answer": "B. Majuli"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. 1982",
              "B. 1985",
              "C. 1987",
              "D. 1992"
            ],
            "question": "In which year, Kaziranga was declared a World Heritage Site by UNESCO",
            "answer": "B. 1985"
          },
          {
            "options": [
              "A. Jorhat",
              "B. Majuli",
              "C. Barpeta",
              "D. Sivsagar"
            ],
            "question": "Which place is known as the heart of the Assamese neo-Vaishnavite culture",
            "answer": "B. Majuli"
          }
    ]
}